My mom passed away last year and left
a beautiful vintage necklace to me and my
older brother, with the wish that we keep
it in the family. My brother is financially
stable, owns a home, and has a good
job. I'm a senior in college, drowning in
debt, and this semester's tuition was due with
no way to pay. I asked him if
I could use the necklace as collateral for
a loan, but he flatly refused, saying it
has too much sentimental value. Without telling him,
I sold the necklace to a private collector
for enough to cover my tuition and books.
When he found out, he exploded, calling me
a thief who disrespected our mother's memory. He
said I should have moved home, taken a
semester off, anything but selling her last gift.
I feel awful because I know how much
it meant to him, but I also think
it's unfair that he gets to decide its
fate when he's not the one panicking about
being homeless or dropping out. Mom would have
wanted me to finish my degree; that's what
she always said. But I've lost my brother
over this, and I can't even look at
old photos without guilt.