Am I the asshole for not letting my
ex-husband visit our dying dog? My ex-husband and
I divorced three years ago after a decade
of marriage that ended because of his emotional
abuse and controlling behavior. The only good thing
from those years was Max, the golden retriever
we got as a puppy. When we split,
I took Max because my ex traveled constantly
for work and couldn't care for him. We
live in different states now, and for my
mental health, I've maintained strict no contact except
for legal necessities. Max is now twelve and
has terminal cancer. The vet says he has
maybe weeks. Somehow my ex found out through
a mutual friend and called me sobbing, begging
to come say goodbye. He says Max was
like his child and he deserves closure. I
refused. I still panic when I hear his
voice, and I can't have him in my
home or even meet him at a park
without reliving the terror. My family says I'm
being cruel because Max loved him and it's
just one last visit. But I know he'll
use this to worm back into my life,
and I've worked too hard to rebuild myself.
I feel guilty because Max looks for him
sometimes, but my safety has to come first.
Am I the asshole?