Would I be the asshole if I told
my sister her husband is cheating with my
best friend? I accidentally discovered that my best
friend Lia has been sleeping with my sister's
husband, Mark. I saw them together at a
hotel when I was there for a work
event. I confronted Lia, and she confessed, crying
that it "just happened" and they're "in love."
Mark refuses to come clean to my sister,
who is six months pregnant with their first
child. Lia begged me not to tell, saying
it would destroy my sister's pregnancy and break
our family apart. She argued that I'd be
ruining multiple lives over a mistake. But my
sister has a right to know, especially with
a baby on the way. Every time I
see her smiling and decorating the nursery, I
feel like I'm swallowing glass. If I stay
silent, I'm complicit in the betrayal. If I
speak up, I risk my sister's health from
stress, lose my best friend forever, and potentially
cause Mark to leave her when she's most
vulnerable. I lie awake every night wondering if
the truth is worth all the pain it
would cause, or if some secrets are better
kept for the greater good. Would I be
the asshole for telling?